# **Jared Diehl**

# Software Engineer

Analytically-driven programmer with five solid years of experience in object-oriented programming and scripting. Well-versed in all phases of the software development life cycle, with a strong working knowledge of algorithms and data structures. Enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlining and innovating. Effective, focused, and motivated software developer proactively furthering my knowledge of system design and architecture in web applications, machine learning, and home automation.

## **Personal Info**

#### **Phone**

314-629-1836

#### E-mail

jared@jaredible.net

#### **GitHub**

github.com/jaredible

#### **WWW**

jaredible.net

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jared-michael-diehl/

# Languages

C#
CSS
HTML
Java
JavaScript
SQL
C++
C
Python
Bash
PHP

# **Technologies**

Express.js	
Git	
MS Office	
Node.js	
.Net	
MongoDB	
MySQL	
Angular	
AWS	
Docker	
Kubernetes	
Nginx	•
React	

# Experience

## 2018-10 - Application Developer

#### present

True Manufacturing

- Developed a strong working knowledge of Epicor ERP
- Designed and developed solutions using Epicor ERP integrating with JDE ERP
- Utilized Agile methodology consisting of daily Scrum Master meetings and Sprints
- Full utilization of the software development life cycle
- · Discovered and documented simple solutions in Epicor ERP
- Utilized SharePoint trackers and user stories for solution management

## 2018-06 -

## .Net Developer

2018-08

Accenture Intern, Ameren Contractor

- Developed a program tracker for program leaders that shortened program review
- Utilized Agile methodology consisting of weekly Scrum Master meetings and Sprints
- Created automated Sharepoint workflows to update program tracker content
- Developed understanding of robotic process automation (RPA)

## **Education**

#### 2017-08 -

## **University of Missouri - Saint Louis**

present

- Pursuing BS, Computer Science
- · Pursuing Minor, Mathematics
- 4.0 GPA
- Computing Club Treasure
- Computing Club's Lead Developer for Art Department Queueing System

#### 2015-08 -

# **Saint Charles Community College**

2017-05

- Completed General Education
- 3.25 GPA
- Student Government Event Organizer

## 2017-07 -

#### Launchcode

2018-08

- Full-Stack development using Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, .Net, and Microsoft SQL
- Proved understanding of Agile methodologies and DevOps principles
- Learned to develop a cryptocurrency tracking application on Android using Kotlin
- Project Manager of a web/mobile application for medication reminders

## Interests

- Home Automation
- Raspberry Pi Clusters
- ML Predictive Movement
- Automatous Vehicles

## **Additional Activities**

Speedcube Competition Organizer, World Cube Association since February 2017

Volunteer Web Developer, World Cube Association since January 2018

Home Automation, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, and Alexa Voice Services

Lead Developer, Computing Club's Lead for Art Department's Queueing System

Hackathon Competitor, GlobalHack VII, BoilerMake VI, UMSL|Hack IV